# **Eduardo** Salcedo

Miami, FL 🏫

(786) 298-3357



salcedo.eduardo@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/eduardosalcedo00 in

Instructor and Ph.D. candidate with seven years of experience teaching university students for associate and bachelor programs. Expertise working with learners of different levels, from dual-enrollment to graduate school. Educational background in Information Systems. Over six years in leadership positions with a focus in providing outstanding customer service. Experienced with conflict resolution and working in a multi-ethnic, multi-cultural environment.

### **Education**

**EXPECTED GRADUATION SUMMER 2023** 

Ph.D. in Information Systems/Florida International University, Miami, FL

JULY 2015

M.S. in Information Systems/Florida International University, Miami, FL

MAY 2013

B.A.S in Supervision and Management/Miami Dade College, Miami, FL

## Leadership

- Chaired the enrollment team for Networking and Computer Information technology programs for the Women RISE grant
- Served as Convener for the Networking discipline committee for EnTec
- Served in the inaugural Learning Outcomes Committee (LOC) as First Vice Chair, leading the team into creating change for MDC's ten Learning Outcomes
- Contributed to the offering and instruction of the CCC in Help Desk Support Technician at my home campus as part of the Rapid Credentialing Program
- Created student club and became president-elect of the Business Doctoral Students Association at Florida International University (54 students)
- Experienced in leading multi-ethnic, multi-cultural teams
- Use of organizational data to present insights to upper management

## **Experience**

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

Instructor | Miami Dade College, Miami, FL

- Built courses for introductory and advanced courses in a higher education institution
- Increased course offerings and brought industry certifications to home campus
- Taught technology courses for basic computer literacy, database design and creation, data management, programming languages (Python, Java), as well as those aimed at preparing students for industry certifications (CompTIA A+, Network+; Microsoft MD-100, MD-101; Python Coding Specialist)

 Trained fellow faculty and departmental staff in use of technology tools such as Zoom, Canvas and Blackboard LMS

JANUARY 2018 - PRESENT

#### Instructor | Florida International University, Miami, FL

• Created courses focusing on data analytics (R and Excel) and application development (Java)

AUGUST 2016 - MAY 2020

#### Teaching and Research Assistant | Florida International University, Miami, FL

- Assisted professors with research projects and classroom management
- Built course curriculum on Canvas and Blackboard for graduate and undergraduate student courses
- Provided online help sessions with video conferencing tools (shared screens, remote control) as well as face-to-face sessions during office hour
- Advised students by answering inquiries regarding pathways to technology professions

AUGUST 2015 - DECEMBER 2019

#### Adjunct Faculty | Miami Dade College, Miami, FL

Taught technology courses in different campuses

NOVEMBER 2013 - AUGUST 2016

#### Guest Service Team Leader & Property Management Lead | Target Corporation, Miami, FL

- Managed the Guest services are of the store (team of 30+)
- Managed the infrastructure, repairs, and supervised vendors working on repairs and upgrades in the store

NOVEMBER 2012 - NOVEMBER 2013

Receiving Clerk | First Service Residential, Miami, FL

JULY 2010 - NOVEMBER 2012

Valet Supervisor | US Parking Associates, Miami, FL

NOVEMBER 2008 - JULY 2010

ACCESS Disability Services Tutor | Miami Dade College, Miami, FL

## **Skills**

• Database design and tools (MySQL, SQL Server) • Data Analytics (Tableau, R) • Programming languages (Java, Python, HTML, CSS, PHP) • Statistical packages (SPSS, SAS) • Windows (11, 10, 8, 7), MacOS, Virtualization Software • Microsoft Office 365, SharePoint, Teams, Zoom, Adobe (Connect, Acrobat, Sign, Captivate) • Languages: English, Spanish (Proficient, native)

## **Memberships**

- PhD Project member and past president
- Association for Information Systems (AIS)
- Business Doctoral Student Association